<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<text type="letters">
    <letter n="1">
        <metaData>
            <date of="08_07_1917">
                <month of="year">July</month>
                <day of="month">8th,</day>
                <year of="1917">1917</year>
            </date>
        </metaData>
        <!--I know this is repeating but I wanted to stay consistent with the year attribute-->
        <body of="letter"><day of="week">Friday</day>
            <time of="day">night</time> we entered the <location>war zone</location> at <time
                is="19:00">seven o'clock</time> but you would never know it. Aside from boat-drills
            and sleeping on deck people act as usual. The officers on the boat are very particular
            about the drills; several times the alarm has sounded and we have been taught just what
            to do in case we are hit. <opinion of="writer">It's very funny to see the people rush
                below for their valuables, strapping on their life preservers as they go
                </opinion><sideThought of="writer">(which we always have near at hand wherever we
                are -on deck or in the saloon)</sideThought>. <start of="drill"/>In about five
            minutes we are lined up, divided into groups in front of our own particular life-boats
            which have been swung out over the sea ready to lower. Every one is checked off and each
            man is told what woman he is to save. <sideThought of="writer">(Great excitement at this
                point as no one of the men wants to save the lady detailed to him, but some one in
                another boat!)</sideThought> We all stand about looking too absurd and bumping into
            each other's life preservers on the crowded upper deck. Finally the signal is given
            which releases us, and we all file down again to take off the clumsy heavy jackets of
            safety and regale ourselves with various amusements on the deck.<end of="drill"
            /><!--I hope I used the self closing elements correctly--> Rumor has it that two ships
            have been sunk, one in the course ahead of where we were yesterday and the other about
            an hour behind us. No one knows how many lives were lost. Perhaps those three submarines
            were more fact than fiction after all. It is thought that we should make Bordeaux by
            Tuesday morning if all goes well and that the convoy which should have met us days ago
            will be with us to-night. <day is="sunday">This being Sunday, the boys on board are very
                much dressed up, that is to say they are wearing clean shirts and have their hair
                brushed! It's a perfect day, <weather>warm and cloudless</weather>, and <action
                    type="tanning">I've been lying in the sun adding to my coat of tan.</action> We
                all feel quite <emotion of="everyone">sad</emotion> that the voyage is so nearly
                over <opinion of="writer">-it has been such loads of fun and I shall hate saying
                    good-by to every one.</opinion>
            </day></body>
        <ship with="writer">La Touraine</ship>
    </letter>


    <letter n="2">
        <metaData>
            <travel of="writer">
                <location direction="from">En route from Bordeaux</location>
                <location direction="to">to Paris,</location>
            </travel>
            <date of="18_07_1917">
                <month of="year">July</month>
                <day of="year"> 18th, </day>
                <year of="1917">1917.</year>
            </date>
        </metaData>
        <body of="letter">
            <action type="arrival">On landing <day of="17_07_1917">yesterday</day> I went straight
                to the <location>Hôtel de France</location> and it certainly was good to have room
                to turn around in: as for a bed with real springs I greeted it with
                    <emotion>enthusiasm!</emotion> Towards <time of="day">evening</time>
                <group of="walk">Frank and I</group> took a long walk about the city.</action> A
            port town always interests me and we saw it all at the loveliest time of
                day.<description of="harbor"> The harbor was full of fishing smacks and small craft
                of all kinds and exquisite tones in the sails and rigging. The last rays of the sun
                cast a rosy hue over everything, making one think at once of Venice and the days
                before the war.</description><action of="frankANDwriter"> Later we wandered through
                some of the oldest parts of Bordeaux</action> and <emotion of="writer">I really felt
                that I was abroad again!</emotion><setting> The narrow winding streets and
                cobblestones, with here and there an ancient façade or doorway and everywhere, in
                the poorest alleys, a bit of a vine or potted plant in the windows.
                </setting><question of="selfReflection">How do they manage to make it all so
                picturesque and alluring?</question> The women and the old men are doing everything
            and it is <emotion>surprising</emotion> to see the lady conductors. On this train they
            use women entirely, even in the dining car. The war hasn't robbed them of vivacity or
            their beautiful complexions and I believe they are even prettier in their simple black
            working clothes than before. <setting>We are at present passing through the famous
                vineyards and I have never seen the country look so beautiful.</setting> The crops
            seem in perfect condition, thanks to the patient labor of these wonderful women, and the
            grain waves in profusion everywhere. I have longed for you at every turn, how you would
            enjoy it all. The poppies are in their prime and, as the train whirls by, they look like
            immense splashes of red -almost like stains of blood against the gold of the wheat.
                <action type="eating">I have just come in from a very excellent meal in the dining
                car</action> -the food was served promptly by two French girls of the peasant type
            and with a speed that was wonderful, the car holding over thirty persons.</body>
        <location of="letter">Paris</location>
    </letter>
    <!--When copied and line wrapped there were still spaces separating certain areas.. i pretty printed without doing any more structure first. -->

</text>
